95% of agentic projects fail. But the
reason for that failure is likely 99% of
engineers, programmers, developers,
project managers don't know how to
actually build aic [music] system. I
think this is something that a lot of
developers currently don't notice about
AI. Like it will implement the task as
you told it to, but it's still lacking
the hey, let's stop for a second. We
need to refactor the code because I find
this common layer or whatever.
Interactivity is the differentiator
factor like when you're using an ID with
a extension uh like a store you're
always checking what happens and you're
just doing this interactively.
[music]
UI elements like simplifies uh and uh um
you know like accelerates the on
boarding um for you as a developer. It
doesn't replace you as a developer. It's
just like here on the side exist to help
you with achieving like specific tasks
like executing uh helping you to write a
specific code file or specific unit
tests and so on and be very uh helpful
in the sense that there is a UI. You
don't need to know any commands because
there are buttons and uh it's just like
a box for you to type the text and
execute. Um I think like the cool uh
part of the Corsor or Windsurf is that
they are giving you this IDE uh with um
with lots of UI elements to help you uh
on board to using these tools more like
proactively and in your everyday use
case. While for AI agents like with
terminal by definition like you don't
need like uh buttons right uh like
complex things complex things can be
done just with a combination of the of
the of the of the keys uh or the
commands. So terminal is like for more
advanced users uh for those who are
ready to accelerate even further because
they don't need to have have
visualization. they are okay just like
leaving in the terminal and manipulating
all the commands in the terminal because
if you're at some point advanced the VH
or Nana or whatever editor uh or a git
you actually don't need UIs right you
can just do and achieve very hard
scenarios with terminal directly and it
saves you time but again like it's just
like a bit harder because it's less
interactive because it's easier to to
lose what happens um and I think the the
amount ount of the generated information
sometimes may be overwhelming. So it's
hard to navigate through the terminal
just because there's so many things are
happening and it requires some skill to
learn how to use it properly.
>> Yeah, absolutely. And I think things
like cursor for example where you see
the the the changes and you can flick
from file to file very very easily. You
obviously miss that from the from the
terminal point of view. But I don't know
what it is about you know just being a
terminal that actually just makes me
feel faster, more productive at the
terminal. Um, and of course when you're
at the terminal, you get the power of
the terminal, right? It's it's tell us a
little bit about how you can effectively
use the terminal beyond just cloud code.
When you build an app in B 44 these
days, like there's a lot of
infrastructure and setup that happens
before the LLM even writes code
>> that in some ways limits it but not
really not in terms of like what it
needs to but it's kind like it it those
are guard rails that the LLM should keep
>> and as long as it keeps that then then
it should be fine to some degree. Um so
again we automatically create the entire
uh uh read update delete kind like the
CRUD SDK and and we make it like really
good and we implement like rate limits
on top of that and things like that that
LM wouldn't really care about and when
you leverage
um I don't know APIs and integrations
and so on like we kema
there's like a lot of things that we
implement mented built into the
application so that LLM won't kind like
be this reward seeking of like I'll do
whatever but I'll I'll keep your app
exposed and and so on. The other the
other thing is yes at some points uh we
automatically feedback the LLM whether
the user knows about it or not that it
needs to refactor something. So for
example, uh one of the things that makes
LLM confused the most um and people feel
that like across the the the VIP coding
category is uh when they're saying like
hey I asked it to do something it didn't
do it it did the opposite it deleted a
feature or whatever um is when code
files are are getting too long. uh right
>> right if if like you've implemented so
you ask it initially or early on hey
implement this page create a to-do list
and it did something simple it's like a
very simple to-do list up like in any
other react and then start layering in
features right so the LM does what what
you asked it to and and it start adding
like uh AI features to write the tasks
description and then user management to
like assign different teams and boards
and whatever and at some point you have
like if you're not careful, you might
have like this very large code file.
>> So, one of the things is like we're
running behind the scenes refactoring
tests uh to maybe tell the LLM, hey,
like you pass the threshold, you should
now refactor this file, even if like
okay, the user ask you something. First,
refactor the file, then implement what
the user has asked you to. And I think
like there's a lot more to do there. But
yeah, it's somewhat of like this uh code
quality agent that that's keep nudging
the LLM at some points if it finds that
it's past a threshold of like hey like
there's this code here and this code
here like do something refactor that
>> look at the state of Agentic today. What
would you say are kind of the things
that are creating that ceiling for for
for Agentic today? What are what are the
biggest things that causing a Gentic uh
development to to fail or at least to to
to cause problems to developers trying
to use a Gentic development today? the
limiting factors of the space right now.
And there was an interesting report from
MIT a couple weeks ago, I think it was,
that basically said 95% of agentic
projects fail. And it was a a fair a
fairly sort of sensational title and and
when you when you dig into that a little
bit, you there there's two ways to to to
think about those types of sort of
stats. one,
you know, 95% of projects fail, which is
probably true, but the reason between
for that failure is likely 99% of of
engineers, programmers, developers,
project managers don't know how to
actually build agentic systems and it's
a byproduct of a new emerging space. And
it and it's so the the limiting factor
is the fact that it's really hard to to
look beyond the sort of um you know I
call it AI washing the agentic washing
of products and the and the people
associated with it to determine you know
what the capabilities of the products
and the people implementing these
products really are. So when you see
this sort of high failure rate it speaks
to the fact that we're in a new emerging
space. And when you go, if you're old
enough to have been around at the
beginning of the internet, you would
have seen the same thing with a lot of
the internet projects that corporations
took on back in the late 90s. And there
was this sort of, you know, this idea
that the internet wasn't quite going to
cut it for most business type
applications. And then they were wrong.
It was the fact that we didn't as a
industry understand exactly how to build
userfriendly internet-based
applications. And over time there were
models to follow. Amazon's and the eBays
and whatnot showed up and we're like
okay this is how you create a web-based
service that people can easily interact
with and it's not just recreating
software. Same problem 25 years later 30
years later in theics and AI space.
There's a tendency for people to build
applications the way they've always
built them with with human centric
models, uh, review cycles, long drawn
out sprints, um, and different sort of,
you know, traditional tactics that were
optimized for a world where we built
slowly over time and gradually. Now,
we're in a world where we can literally
copy anything anywhere at at a moment's
notice. and the ability the the quality
of the code although important is less
important than the momentum that you get
in terms of speed and time to market. So
when you're looking at companies that
are embracing this they're they're
embracing this in a way that doesn't
just replace their developers that that
might be a byproduct but it augments
them in ways that those developers were
never able to do before. So you're
empowering them with sort of a kind of
superpower to to to create much more
effectively and much more quickly which
in itself creates a whole variety of
secondary problems. But ultimately this
is this is the empowerment of developers
to to do more with less.